RYAN H S

ryan@vloro.com (62) - 85720759240

PROGRAMMER

Profile

Starting as web developer, and have a wide perspective of lots of things in programming. from critical mission C application & cutting-edge web developer to Artificial Intelligence.

Skills

Web Developer

Experienced about 4 years in web development.

C Programmer

Some project need critical mission where C is the best solution. No doubt about it.

Artificial Intelligence

As researcher today, Artificial Intelligence is a trend right

Technical

HTML5	Laravel	Linux
Javascript	CodeIgniter	Windows
SASS & LESS	C for Web	

Experience

Pasebandotcom

PHP Programmer

April 2011 - December 2011

Start working after doing national exam in vocational high school. as young programmer gain experience.

CV Pusat Link.

Full Stack Programmer (System & Web)

Learn become senior programmer. Build complex API server.

January 2012 - March 2012

CV Techno

Full Stack Programmer (System & Web)

Partner company of CV Pusat Link.

March 2012 - August 2012

PT Topi Putih Kreasi Indonesia

Web Programmer, Technical advisor

Learn to be responsible in lots of project.

October 2012 - january 2014

PT Voxteneo Indonesia

PHP Programmer

September 2014 - July 2015

Learn lots of experience in proffesional attitude and technical knowledge in very large project.

Education

SMKN 4 Bandung - (Vocational High School)

Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak (Software Engineering)

STMIK "amikbandung"

Teknik Informatika (Computer Science/Informatics) 3.53 GPA

Institut Teknologi Bandung (ITB)

Teknik Elektro Option Teknik Media Digital dan Game (Master degree) in progress:-)

Awardee

Mahasiswa Program Beasiswa Unggulan, yang Mendapat Prestasi di Bidang

Teknologi Informasi BPKLN Kemdikbud RI **2012**

TIM Website Dinas Pendidikan / Penerimaan Peserta Didik Baru (PPDB) Kota

Bandung

STMIK "amikbandung" 2013

Volunteer / Opensource Contribution

CSPY PHP Framework

a minimalist php framework i created in high school :-)

before i know about codeigniter etc.. 2009

CI TPL

an admin system for Codeigniter 2.x, since there is Codeigniter 3 has been released. This is about to dicontinued, only maintain existed project. **2011**

Encylopedia

JS Classes for handling really large data in Javascript, Registered in JS Classes ${\bf 2015}$

Genetic Algorithm Toolkit in PHP

toolkit focused on build genetic algorithm application with costumized schema, composer: ryanhs/genetic-algorithm-tooklit 2015

PPDB Kota Bandung

Yearly event when student apply for Elementary/Junior High School/Senior High School 2011 - now (yearly event)

TIM Website Dinas Pendidikan / Penerimaan Peserta Didik Baru (PPDB) Kota

STMIK "amikbandung" 2013

Seminar Portfolio (as speaker)

Hacking Black or White

UNPAD **2009**

Make Your Linux Powerfull

UNPAD **2010**

Web Design and Security in 2014 and Web Hacking Demo

STMIK "amikbandung" 2013

The Future of Android

Universitas Sangga Buana 2014

Workshop Portfolio
(as trainer)

Workshop Hacking
STMIK "amikbandung" 08-19 February 2010

Workshop Hacking
STMIK "amikbandung" 01-12 March 2010

Journal
Portfolio

Komparasi Algoritma Pengurutan Untuk Penerimaan Peserta Didik Baru Kota
Bandung
Tati Suprapti, Ryan Hamonangan - UNJANI (2015)

Ryan H Silalahi — ryan@vloro.com — (62) - 85720759240